## Vandish Gandhi

+61 450602494 vandish009@hotmail.com

#### Profile

I am an experienced lead frontend developer who is strongly focused on javascript(primarily frontend) ecosystem. I have React, Angular, Vue and Ember's commercial experience of 6+ years. I am ICAgile certified for agile fundamental practices and a team player ranging from my primary specialisation on the front-end to API engineering and infrastructure setup for cross platform apps. In conjunction with proven people/(pro)developers management skills, I host a strong project, resource and development management skills.

#### Education

Master of Business (Information Systems & ERP) - Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia (2013) Bachelor of Computer Application - Gujarat University, India (2011)

#### **Industry Experience**

#### Frontend Lead for Adslot (November 2018 – Present)

Responsible for:

- Contributing to front-end decision-making and architecture
- Maintaining team focus on reusable code, patterns and libraries
- Optimising application for maximum performance, maintainability and Scalability
- Maintaining open-source UI pattern libraries in React
- Collaborating and communicating with Front-End/Full-Stack Developers and stakeholders
- Mentoring, training and organising other Developers
- Conducting thorough and constructive code-reviews and unit-tests

**Direct Reports:** 3 Frontend devs

#### **Application Stack:**

Front end: React with Redux and Context API, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Angular JS & Coffee Script.

Project Management Tools: Atlassian Jira, Confluence & Microsoft Sharepoint.

Source Control: Github, Jenkins (CI)

#### Senior/Lead Frontend Developer for Telstra (August 2017 – November 2018)

Project: Prepaid Activation (https://telstra.com.au/prepaidactivation)
Responsible for:

- Leading and maintaining frontend application for prepaid activation.
- Creating reusable AEM components for authoring and hosting SPA on AEM 6.3
- Driving the UX to make sure the application is responsive on web development, cross-browser and platform agnostic.

- Mentoring offshore developers in React development and ensure smooth bi-weekly development cycle with efficient source control management.
- Analysing business requirements to propose software design approach

**Direct Reports:** 4 fullstack, 1 frontend

**Application Stack:** 

Front end: React with Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Less, Bootstrap, JQuery and DOM api. Project Management Tools: Atlassian Jira, Confluence & Microsoft Sharepoint

Source Control: Atlassian Sourcetree/Bitbucket, Git

### Frontend Developer for ERM Power Ltd. (June 2016 – August 2017) Project: Customer Portal (https://myportal.ermpower.com.au)

Responsible for:

- Developing user interface and engineering user experience for customer portal built on EmberJS
- Formulating & standardizing the ERM look and feel across internal and external projects
- Analysing business requirements to propose software design approach
- Driving the customer facing look and feel of ERM Web user interfaces
- Designing collateral mock ups for marketing and business units;
- Providing guidance for user experience and system implementation.

#### **Application Stack:**

Front end: Ember.js, HTML5, CSS3, Saas, Bootstrap

Backend: ASP.NET MVC, C#

# Software Developer for University of Technology (June 2015 – June 2016) Project: Farm management dashboard

Responsible for:

- Developing, maintaining and cross platform testing frontend application build on Angular 1.5.
- Integrating Bootstrap, Angular Material and Foundation frameworks to enhance look and feel of web application as required.
- Maintaining instances on AWS, code deployment and load balancing on servers for incoming traffic.

# Software Developer for Bombardier Transportation (June 2014- June 2015) Project: QNGR (Queensland New Generation Rolling stock)

Responsible for:

- Full Stack development using MVC architecture in PHP, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax and jQuery using MySQL as backend database.
- Developing project plans, schedule, budget and risk assessment.

## **Programming Intern for Cosmic Infocom, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India (2010-2011)** *Responsible for:*

- Coding firmware to communicate with PRI interface for call conferencing purposes.
- Designing web application using Microsoft Visual studio in ASP.NET.
- Building database for the client and integrating with web application using MS SQL.

#### **Technical Skills**

Analytics : Adobe Analytics, New Relic

Content Management : AEM, WordPress

Java scripting Framework : React, Angular, Ember, Vanilla js, jQuery, backbone

Web Designing : HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS, SaaS and Less

Automated Testing : Selenium, Jasmine, Karma, Chai, Mocha (Expert)

Reporting Tools : Omniture, Power BI

Operating System : Win NT, XP, 7, 8, Mac OSx,Linux,CentOS
Office Tools : Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access (Expert)
Computer Programming : C, C++, Bash Scripting (Linux), COBOL,Pascal

Server Side Programming : ASP.Net,PHP,ASP.Net MVC, Python,C#,VBA(Event driven)

Source Client Side Scripting : jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript, VBScript

Data Formats : XML, JSON

ERP System : SAP

Project Management tool : Microsoft Project, Atlassian Jira Web Services : REST, SOAP (Working Knowledge)

RDBMS : MYSQL, MS SQL, Oracle Database (Intermediate Skills)

NoSQL : Mongo DB

Source Control Systems : GIT, Github, Sourcetree (GUI), Github GUI

Web server Framework : Apache Xampp, IIS, Hadoop (conceptual understanding)

#### Non-technical Skills

- Excellent oral and written communication skills from various roles and leasing with businesses.
- Proven organisational and time management skills as sole programmer in Bombardier and UTS.
- Developed skills to multi-task and work under demanding conditions from multiple projects.
- Gained an expert skill base in Microsoft Office applications from coursework and industry experience

#### **Certification**

• ICAgile. Certification: Agile professional

- Authority: Australian Computer society. Certification: Analyst Programmer.
- Authority: SAP University Alliance & Victoria University. Certificate of achievement for:
  - o Business Intelligence systems
  - o Advanced Business Application Programming(ABAP)

#### **Hobbies and Interest**

Photography, snooker and travelling.